Hello Everybody,
14th June - Leaving alone for the first time

Travelling Alone


Today for the first time ever in my life I started to travel to an unknown place (unvisited by me). I left for Secunderabad from my house at 6:45 PM in auto which my mom boarded me into. I went in that auto till the Naveen Studio and took my VISA size photos and then caught another auto till KPHB and went in 3rd auto for 90 Rs to Secunderabad station.(Rs (4+3+90)).

After entering the station, at 8:15 PM, I went and asked the TT where the charminar express will come. He said Platform number 1 and then I waited till 8:30 PM and then found that it was written on the platform where which bogey will be halting So I went walking till the end of the station but didnt find AS2 the I walked the whole way back and found that the place where I was in the beginning is the place where AS2 Bogey will be coming.I then waited and as soon as the train came I went and sat in my seat. 

The other people with me in the octet (or whatever) were one old pair,one new pair, one Kannada uncle and one Telugu aunty. I thought of sleeping as soon as I came into the train but I waited till TT came and checked the Tickets and then I slept at 930 PM after asking the old uncle when chennai will come. He said 1030 AM.

NEXT DAY in TRAIN

Morning I woke up at 6 AM and freshed up and then again slept and waited for ther others to wake up as there was no place to sit in the seats in the lower berths as mine was the upper berth. As soon as they folded the train seat I climbed down and waited for Chennai talking to the old uncle about how to reach the US Embassy or Consulate and where to stay. 

CHAT before Chennai 

While I was talking to uncle we entered Tamil nadu at around 8:30 AM as my cell informed me that "WELCOME tO TAMIL NADU....."  and as soon as we entered instead of selling breakfast,coffee and Tea ,people started selling Pirated Movie DVDs. Some of those DVDs even had Pokiri,Bangaram and Chatrapati in one DVD as a combo and was priced at 60 Rs. And english they had Da Vinci Code, MI3 and POSIEDON in one DVD. But those all would be definitely CAM prints so I didnt waste money by buying those. Uncle told me how to travel to VISA CONSULATE,ANNA SALAI 220,GEMINI CIRCLE. I just followed those instructions after I got down.

Cheanni Central at 1030 AM


At exactly 1030 AM we arrived at Chennai central station. My first aim was to eat something as I didnt eat anything while on train for breakfast. I got down and realized that once long time ago we had a break journey through Chennai and we stopped at this station for a few hours. Anyways I walked on to the Tiffin Center and ate a plate IDLY (MY FAV). They gave many types of Chutney to taste with 2 Idlys. I didnt like it much.

Then I crossed the road, after asking the traffic police which way i have to goto US VISA CONSULATE, using the subway. Very developed roadways there. The people rarely cross the roads and come in way of the vehicles. After crossing the road I called mom and informed her of me reaching Chennai. As i was in roaming even incoming costed me 2 Rs a minute. I didnt accept many calls other than from my family members. 

FINDING MY WAY TO US CONSULATE

I took the bus as suggested by uncle in train and went to Gemini Circle with the help of one Tamil kid who understood what i said but couldnt reply me in any language which I could understand. He informed the conductor to tell me when Gemini Circle comes. He even offered me an empty seat without he sitting in it, maybe coz he saw me with my heavy backpack. Thanks to the Kid and the conductor I got down at Gemini Circle. 

From there I kept asking people where US Conulate was and kept walking in the direction they pointed. After walking around a Kilometer or half I came back to the main road with the Gemini Fltover. I walked back in the bus route and after lots of roaming found the EMBASSYYY or US consulate. After seeing where it was, I asked the Security guard where I could find a nice nearby hotel for accomodation. He told me about CRYSTAL RESIDENCY. I went there. It was just across the road.

FOUND CONSULATE NOW TO FIND ACCOMODATION

I crossed the road using a subway and I was in front of the hotel. The hotel was real good. And the price also was reasonable. A SINGLE AC room for 24 Hours was 950 Rs plus tax. But unfortunately as I asked for it they said no rooms were available. Later they told me that in 1 hour one room will be emptied and I could take it. I dindt wanna wait so long. So, hoping for some other hotels I went ahead but found all very low class jhopdi type rooms for 140 to 300 rent per day. I returned back to crystal residency and found the room would be ready in 20 minutes.

ROOM AT CRYSTAL RESIDENCY

I called dad and he said to ask ISMAIL Uncle for any help regarding hotels who is in chennai, but he was of no use. I just waited for some time saw if the room quality and the price were in balance and took it as I found it reasonable. I paid the amount first as they usually take the money before itself and then went to room,had a nice bath and rested till 2 PM from 1 PM and then went for lunch. 

LUCNH TIME

The hotels restaurant was too busy. They asked me to wait for 1 hour. SO i just went for a walk and found many nice hotels but i chose a neat small restaurant name KALIMA and had POORI and CHOLE for lunch and it costed me only 18 Rs. Then I went back to the hotel kept all things in a safe place and went out at 4PM to Rich STreet which according to the chennai people is the best place for electronic goods. 

WAY TO RICH STREET

I took the bus according to the reception guy and got down where the conductor asked me to. But I found myself very far away from RICH STREET, this I realized after reaching the Rich street after 30 minutes of walk. Everyone were telling me to go straight so kept goin, besides , I didnt want to waste money on auto for such a small distance.

On my way to rich street I found many nice buildings and took photos in my cell. As soon as i reached rich street I started looking for PS2 games which my bro wanted. I found only one nice PS2 games shop and took 1 game, BLACK (Rs.45). Then on asking this guy about movie DVDs he sent me to some other shop where they were available. I just had a look and found all boring titles. I asked him how to goto the BEACH. He told me the path and said it was 3 Km and auto would cost around 15Rs. So i kept shopping for sometime till 615PM and bought some stuff. There are many DVD shops in chennai was a great view to look at. Jaha dekho waha Movies ke DVDs.

THE GOOD JUICE MAKER

Then I had a Pineapple juice for 10 Rs. In huderabad when we ask for Pineapple juice they add water into on slice of pineapple piece to make it one glass, but in chennai when i said one Pineapple juice he took a whole PINEAPPLE and gave me in 1 and a half BIG glass and said these both glasses are yours, the other half is Bonus and all that only for 10 Rs.

TO THE BEACH

From there I took an auto for 20 Rs to the BEACH. Dont know which beach it was but it was a beach alright. At first sight I thought it was a desert coz it was long way till the water. I walked like a person in a desert till the water and felt very happy to see cool drinks and water over there. All the people were enjoying the water waves. I took pictures and video even with myself in it. At first I thought I wouldnt enter the water as I wouldnt have anyone to watch my sandals when i go in, but while walking alongside the beach I found some people hlolding their sandal in the water. So I too folded my heavy jeans and went into the water holding snadals in one hand and camera in other. 

ABSENT MINDED WASH AWAY

I took many pictures. I took so many that I fogot i was in water and I dindt see the big wave coming. While i was cliking the pics the big wave almost washed me away into the water but I was ok. Only my pants became a bit wet dur to the water. I then enjoyed till 7PM and then walked back in the desert after having a coke.

WAY TO SPENCER PLAZA

The police men told me to catch a 47b/y bus for going to spencers plaza and the people at bus stop told me to catch 27h/l but none of those buses came or halted at the bus stop so after waiting till 7 50 PM I took an auto for 35 Rs till Spencers plaza and entered it. I was a BBBIIIIG shopping mall like the Rashi'd mall in Saudi. Very nice. but all were closing as I was moving as it was 830PM. I moved to music world and beside that was a EASY RECHARGE center .i.e. a stand with all kinds of chargers for cellphones, here we can charge our cell phone if out of battery. Very help ful for some.

Then I took many photos, walked with forigh girls and then went to eat at pizza hut which was at the last floor. Had a heavy dinner of 130 RS and walked back home (hotel = 3KMs) in the night at 10:00 PM. While walking I found people selling the movie DVDs of all kind on the road for 50 Rs.

Going from GREAT day to BIG day

After reaching the room at 1030 PM I made everything ready for the next day (the VISA INTERVIEW day) and then slept watching the ENG VS TRI World cup and sending Email throught cell attacheing the photos taken today. I left my cell on for the whole night by mistake and slept. 

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

16th JUNE - THE BIG DAY IS HERE

KUKUDOOOKO

Woke up with the cell phone alarm at 6 AM and found the cell in GPRS MODE. The 2 Mb mail was sent but due to the GPRS the cell charge was 1 bar low. I dint think of charging coz i just charged it yesterday. 

Breakfast

I then Freshed up and went for a walk to the same KALIMA restaurant as it was the only tiffin center which was open at that time. I went there in my night dress itself. Ate 2 plates idli and the bill was only 18 Rs again (same as Chole Pori yesterday). After that I walked back to the hotel and had a nice warm bath.

READY TO CHECK OUT

Then packed everything and kept ready for check out as I wasnt sure at what time i will be back from the interview(my check out time was 12 43 PM). I got ready, went to the receptionist, and told him that If I wont be back by my checkout time keep my bag out and keep it in your office. But he didnt agree and gave his own Idea. He asked me to check out now itself and give the bag to them and they will keep in the office. I said ok even though I though I might need the room after interview for some time.

READY TO GO

I then kept my cell in silent mode and went to the interview in embassy, which was across the street. After asking the guard there abt the line he asked me to stand in the line if i had an appointment. I was there at 830 AM while mine was at 9 AM. As soon as the clock struck 845 AM the guard asked for people with 9 AM appointment and asked them if they had any cell phone, Floppy or CDS and asked to leave it out and go in. I had cell phone with me . There was no locker here. Even though Rafiq told me all these are not allowed I forgot and took my cell like a fool.

THE LOCKER PROBLEM 

The guard told me taht the police guy wil take me to a locker. I followed him and he too me to a chai stand and as soon as I saw thta I though it would be better if I kept in the hotel and came. I was just startin to run when a guy called me and asked if i wanted a locker. He pulled me by my hand and forced me to put my cell in that chai stand locker. When I saw what that locker was I felt like kicking those people. They were rolling the cell in a newspaper and writing number on it. and besides this they were asking 100 Rs for this bakwaas. I just snatched my cell from his hands and walked away with an angry face towards the hotel.

THE LONG WAY TO HOTEL AND BACK 

I gave it to the receptionist and ran back. While crossing the subway I found a begger asking for alms and I gave him 2 Rs hoping everything to be fine. I then reached the gate and entered immediately at 9 AM. Then while checking they asked again if I had anything with me. I was sure I didnt have anything with me but metal detector detected that I had something in my chest pocket. When I looked I found My pen drive . WHAT BAD LUCK . I had no other option but to run again till the hotel. I ran, gave it and returned by 9:15 AM.

ATLAST IN 

I then went in without anymore delays. Then there was a big line on each of the 6 counters. In these counters the people were made to stand in a line according to their appointment timings. As I was late I was a bit behind others. I was made to stand in the first line (0th counter). The person in this counter was very slow, had a french beard, and kept on talking on phone and taking breaks for eating and drinking. Besides this kinda slow processing, people with children , old age and handicaps were given higher priority and were made to barge into the line and get their files fixed before others.

WHAT IS THE FIRST COUNTER FOR?

In this counter we have to give the Passport, I20, SEVIS Fee Receipt, Appointment letter, DS 156,157,158/159 form and the original HDFC bank reciept and they arrnage it accordinng to some order and put in a file along with a form which they put in it.

THE SECOND BIG LINE to SECOND BUILDING

After this, the first counter is over.Now we need to move to the next building which is the main place where the interviews are held. My first counter work was done at 1100 AM. (Yeah, It was very slow indeed). As I came out of my first line the second line also grew very long. I was asked to stand in the end of the line but if i wud do that i wud be too late for my appointment. So I just showed my 9 AM appointment letter and requested a student to let me in the line. No one minded. 

I then asked the staff member if there wud be a problem if i reach late at the interview counter. Then she said that they will call members accordning to the appointment time so i dont need to worry. I was very thirsty after standing in the heating climate of chennai for so long. I went and drank some water whcih was available in front of the line. After some time, an old lady came out of the second building and called people with appointments before 9 AM. I just raised my hand. I was the only one there. And 3 were between 9 and 915 am. We all were asked to make a new line and follow her in. I was first in this line.

ATLAST INSIDE THE SECOND BUILDING

After going in I found around 12 counters. Till now I was thinking that the interview will be done in a room where the person will be seated and we wil be sitting in a chair facing him and we wil be asked questions. But it was totally different. These 12 counters were the interview counters for various kinds of people. ctaegorized according to interview language. In one it was TELUGU interview in other was TAMIL interview etc. 3 were for English Interview.

TENSION DUE TO CONFUSION

First I was asked to goto counter 8. I though this was the final stage (Interview counter). I gave my passport ,didnt even say Hi,coz i was taken to counter 8 immediately after entering the second building. Here she took my passport and asked me to put my left index finger on the scanner. I almost showed her the wrong finger :p coz in tension i gorgot which finger was which one. She asked me to put my right hand index finger on the scanner. again 2 to 3 times same thing to repeat. The way I was putting my finger on the scanner made her laugh. Then she asked if i had something on my finger. I saw and said No. Then she took returned my passport and said Thank You. and seriously turned her face away. For a moment I WAS IN SHOCK. I thought my visa was rejected coz she returned me the passport. 

COFUSION CLEARED

I then went to the other indian old lady who helped me earlier about this. I explained that she took my passport and returned it back to me and then she siad NOW YOU WAIT FOR YOUR INTERVIEW. These words made me so normal. I was so much in tension when  i got my passport back from her thinking that I was rejected a VISA.

WAITING FOR FINAL STAGE(INTERVIEW)

Then I was made to sit again in the first as time was given priority along iwth the finger printing. I sat and heard how the interviews were going. I was not much tensed now I was cool as an ice cube. Then Mr. Marc (head of teh embassy) came and explained to everybody how to attend an interview. He cracked great jokes and asked us to do three things when going to interview. 1. SMILE 2. WISH 3. BE HONEST with no tension. He warned about fake documents and some other stuff and cracked really cool jokes which made all of us lose our tension.

MISCONCEPTION or WRONG IDEA ABOUT THE INTERVIEW

I was still thinking that the interview wil be in a room with chairs to sit but at 12 PM when I was asked to join the third line I understood that it was a standing interview in public with speakers and microphones(for audibilty through the bullet proof glass). There were 2 guys ahead of me. The guy who was taking our interview was young one and was maybe the youngest among all others. The questions being asked in the other counters were so straight and went in a programmed way while the guy asking us was going round and round around the same question. I think the one taking our interview was testing the patience. The guy ahead of me for job visa was answering very badly and rudely so after 20 minutes of interview his Visa was rejeected.

And the guy before me applying for student visa answered all the questions like a buttified answer.Speed and ununderstandable. He got the Visa anyways.His interview was only 4 minutes. Then came my turn.

ITS MY TURN

I went forward when he asked me to come. Before I could wish him he wished me Good Afternoon. Then I replied with with a smile he too smiled and was looking fine compared to previos interviews.The questions went as follows:

VO: HOW MANY UNIV U APPLIED?
ME: 6

VO: WHICH ONES?
ME: SIUE,UTA,UAB,IIT,UNO,OCU(Full Names)

VO: WHY THIS UNIV?
ME: GOOD FACULTY and INFRASTRUCTURE

VO: WHY THIS UNIV? (Again)
ME: Its a better univ for the computer sciences.

VO: WHY THIS UNIV? (Again)
ME: Suggested by my frnds also that its a better univ compared to the others whcih i got admitted into.

VO: WHY THIS UNIV? (Again)
ME: GOOD FACULTY to STUDNET RATIO

VO: WHATS THE STUDENT FACULTY RATIO?
ME: IT IS THE RATIO......(stopped me in middle)

VO: I KNOW WHATS THE STUDENT FACULTY RATIO!! WHATS THE RATIO?
ME: (Tukka)...around 8:1 or 7:1 

VO: OK
VO: WHY DIDNT U WAIT FOR THE OTHER I20s?
ME: They have started the processing of application just recently and it will be late by the time i get those admssions.

VO: WHAT MADE U TAKE CS?
ME: My background in UG was also CS and I prefer continuing it.

VO: WHY DID U TAKE CS?
ME: I was inclined toward CS since my childhood and have developed interest in it.

VO: WAHT MADE U GET INTEREST IN CS?
ME: I HAVE BEEN around the computers for long time now and have leanrnt a lot thru many books and these are not enough for me to learn all so I chose this as my course.

VO: WAHT MADE U GET INTEREST IN CS?(again)
ME: I have played many games and have wondered how the people developed those. The controlling making the char on screen move and doing what we tell the char to etc. This made me go to programming an graphics side more whcih is also CS.

VO: SO U WHAT U WANT TO DO IN FUTURE?
ME: I WANT TO COMPLETE MS and the get a job here.

VO: WHAT POST WUD U BE IN?
ME: SOFTWARE PROJECT MANAGER

VO: DO U WANT TO GOTO GAME PROGRAMMING SIDE?
ME: ITS NOT SPECIFIC TO GAME PROGRAMMING... I LOVE PROGRAMMING OF ANY SORT..

VO: WHY DO U LOVE PROGRAMMING?
ME: The way which programming makes us think is the best part whcih i like abt programming.

VO: OK
VO: SHOW ME YOUR UG Reports!
ME: showed the CONSOLIDATED MEMO

VO: NO! SHOW ME THE INDIVIDUAL ONES.
ME: SHOWED

VO: GRE TOEFL
ME: sHOWED

VO: OK
VO: SOMETHING ON PC....klik klik.
VO: GAVE back my reports.
VO: Ok...Good Luck...You will be getting your passport withing 3 days.

ME: THANK U and left.

WORRIED

All the time he kept a serious face except in the beginning. When he said the last sentence I was confused whether I got the Visa or not. Usually I heard that VO tells whether we got the visa or not but this guy didnt tell me specifically that i got the Visa or will be gettin it.

ATLEAST ITS OVER

I then anywasy left after asking the staff member wehther the process was over. He said me to leave coz it was over. So I exited and went back to the hotel. Took My cell bag and Pen drive back and sat in the AC after the walk in the HEAT of chennai. As soon as i switched on the cell I got dad's and rafiq's SMS asking abt the VISA. AS I was not sure what happened in there , I called rafiq first and confirmed that I got the Visa because he said that if a visa is rejected they give the passport back there itself. I was still not sure. but as everybody started calling and asking i said that "Yeah I THINK I GOT IT" I got so many calls and sms that my balance in cell was reduced from 350 Rs to 90 RS.

TENSION GONE

After all that tension was settled. I freshened up at the hotel and then sat in Ac till 1 PM and then left for touring chennai after a lunch of FRIED RICE at the restaurant with my luggage (one bag = back pack). Then in an auto for 50 Rs I went to T nagar as i was told that its a good shopping place and was close to the station. 

EXTRA FREE TIME SHOPPING

I went there and found only utensils and clothers and eatables. I asked in many shops for DVDs adn after having a softy for cooling down found a small street with nice shade of tree and followed that street to station. On the way I found 100s of DVD shops. from 2 PM till 430 PM I was searching DVDs and looking for good ones.

Oops Wrong STATION

Then I walked to the station at 430 PM thinking it to be central station while it was a local train station called MAMBLAM. WHen i asked people abt how to reach CENTRAL they suggested local train rather than auto as it wud coz me 50 times more to me in auto. i.e 200 Rs while train 4 rs. I took a ticket and boarded with local people guidance. I found a HYD guy named VISU and spoke to him whil ein train, and got down at CHENNAI FORT and walked to CENTRAL wchih was across the road. Took last pics in CHENNAI and had a coke and then went and sat in the train ftom 510 PM itself while the train leavin time was 618 PM. I took a water bottle,bought tinkle for timepass, Talked to strangers and then the train started exactly at 618 PM according to my watch.

SWEET DREAMS

I slept at 9 PM and in the night there was some fight abt seats whcih i ignored and slept nicely till next day 6AM and freshed up. Just as I freshed up people started waking up and soon all were awake. I talked to them abt new cell phones and mp3 players and we enjoyed. 

BACK TO HOME

After getting down at secbad I ate idly for breakfast and went home in auto direct to home. Called Visu consultancy and now am sure that I got the Visa.  
 